<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper Reading on Shengting Cao&#39;s Note Book</title>
    <link>https://shengtingcao.top/categories/paper-reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper Reading on Shengting Cao&#39;s Note Book</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shengtingcao.top/categories/paper-reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Road Map Papers: Classification </title>
      <link>https://shengtingcao.top/blog/deeplearningpaper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shengtingcao.top/blog/deeplearningpaper1/</guid>
      <description>fundamental papers in classification   Krizhevsky, Alex, Ilya Sutskever, and Geoffrey E. Hinton. &amp;ldquo;Imagenet classification with deep convolutional neural networks.&amp;rdquo; Advances in neural information processing systems. 2012. pdf (AlexNet, Deep Learning Breakthrough)
  Simonyan, Karen, and Andrew Zisserman. &amp;ldquo;Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition.&amp;rdquo; arXiv preprint arXiv:1409.1556 (2014). pdf (VGGNet,Neural Networks become very deep!)
  Szegedy, Christian, et al. &amp;ldquo;Going deeper with convolutions.&amp;rdquo; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Road Map Papers: Segmentation </title>
      <link>https://shengtingcao.top/blog/deeplearningpaper2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shengtingcao.top/blog/deeplearningpaper2/</guid>
      <description>fundamental papers in classification J. Long, E. Shelhamer, and T. Darrell, “Fully convolutional networks for semantic segmentation.” in CVPR, 2015. pdf
Ronneberger O, Fischer P, Brox T. U-net: Convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. InInternational Conference on Medical image computing and computer-assisted intervention 2015 Oct 5 (pp. 234-241). Springer, Cham. pdf
Chen LC, Papandreou G, Kokkinos I, Murphy K, Yuille AL. Deeplab: Semantic image segmentation with deep convolutional nets, atrous convolution, and fully connected crfs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>